Phone 770-617-7755 E-mail: phillip.grider@gmail.com

Phillip W. Grider

Summary of qualifications

Manager of Multiple Entities and Satellite Communication Specialist.

I am an experienced Manager with over 22 years experience in Audio Visual Systems to include Video Conferencing, System Programming, Live Audio design, and Production Video Installation. I am also currently a member if the Alabama Air National Guard. My specialties are in Satellite Communications Deployment and System Planning. I am currently assigned to the Plans and Program Management section of the 232nd Combat Communication Squadron. I currently own my own company providing Programming and Commissioning Services to A/V Contractors, Product Manufacturers around the United States and overseas. I also hold a DOD Secret Level Clearance.

Experience

2010 - Present

Integrated Logic Solutions

Pike Road, Alabama

Owner/Systems Programmer

My current company provides programming and commissioning services for Crestron Electronics commercial lighting systems around the southeastern part of the U.S. I also provide installation supervisory services for IMAX corporation. My duties and responsibilities include managing onsite contractors, train staff and assure the system is operational and meets specification. My company also offers programming support services to A/V contractors around the US from interface design, custom macro creation, and system design.

2008 - 2010

PIVOD Technologies

Alpharetta, Georgia

General Manager of Engineering Services

My job responsibilities included management all design and estimation for PIVOD Technologies in North America. We offer audio/visual installation and services and my responsibilities are to design and estimate cost from concept to completion. I am also responsible for creating line drawings and elevation drawings for all installation work where required. Also I must ensure that all projects have proper documentation and design to provide the end user with a functioning system. I am currently using AutoCAD 10, Visio, and Microsoft Office.

2004 - 2008

Technical Installation Personnel Alpharetta, Georgia

Partner and Engineering Manager

My job responsibilities included all design and cad work as well as any job related estimation. I also manage field teams to ensure that work was completed according to the design and that any deviations were approved prior to implementation. I was over all field installation crews insuring that projects were completed on time and within budget estimates. I worked in a wide variety of AV fields from Houses of Worship, Production Video and Corporate Facilities. I did design work from the new construction of whole room control to upgrades to existing AV systems. I am versed in AutoCAD, Microsoft Office Suite, and Visio.

1999 - 2004

Sonics Associates, Inc.

Birmingham, Alabama

Installation Supervisor

In this position I am responsible for the on-site supervision of numerous trades with the objective of installation of an Imax Sound System. Included in my current position I am responsible for all electronic connections and speaker positioning and aiming. Also, I provide on-site customer training of the Digital Theatre Audio Controller that is custom built for the Imax Theatre.

1994 - 1999

Electronic Engineers

Montgomery, Alabama

Installation Supervisor

My job responsibilities include: Installing and maintaining Nurse Call systems, Pro Sound systems, CCTV systems and School intercom systems. I also have experience in the installation of Teleconferencing, Video Conferencing and Crestron Media Control Systems.

Education

1987 - 1989

Auburn University at Montgomery Montgomery, Alabama

Information Systems

Major courses included: Calculus/Linear Algebra, Accounting, Machine Information systems and various computer classes.

1986 - Present

Military Education

United States Army

In 1986 graduate from the United States Army Computer Operator Coarse.

United States Air Force

In 1990 graduated with Honors from the United States Air Force Electronics School at Keesler Air Force Base in Biloxi, Mississippi..

In 1992 Completed 5-Level TRC-170 Course at Keesler Air Force Base.

In 1999 Completed Just In Time TDC Course for the Promina 400(IDNX-20) in Boston Massachusetts.

In 2000 Completed 7-Level Course for Maintenance Technicians.

In 2007 Completed Course 12 for SNCO Academy